<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Connor Gilroy on Computational Demography @UW</title>
    <link>/computational-demography/author/connor-gilroy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Connor Gilroy on Computational Demography @UW</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/computational-demography/author/connor-gilroy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tidycensus Tutorial</title>
      <link>/computational-demography/post/tidycensus-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computational-demography/post/tidycensus-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Connor Gilroy and Neal Marquez presented a tutorial on downloading and mapping American Community Survey data from the US Census Bureau API, using the tidycensus R package.
You can clone or download the tutorial materials from GitHub, or view the tutorial online at this link.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discussion and Looking Forward</title>
      <link>/computational-demography/post/discussion-and-looking-forward/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computational-demography/post/discussion-and-looking-forward/</guid>
      <description>At the final meeting of the 2018-2019 academic year, we brainstormed ideas for the coming year. We discussed potential speakers, including incoming UW faculty, substantive topics of relevance to the group, and technical topics for tutorials. One idea that emerged was having a series of tutorials throughout the year on creating an R package of benefit to academic researchers. Many participants felt that a package implementing common tools for working with neighborhood-level spatial data would be useful to us, since we often build those tools on our own in an ad-hoc way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a Research Website</title>
      <link>/computational-demography/post/making-a-research-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computational-demography/post/making-a-research-website/</guid>
      <description>Why make a website? Academic researchers need to communicate their work!
Several kinds of websites can be useful for this:
 a personal academic homepage a page for a specific research project a website for a course a website for a working group or seminar (like CDWG!)  Key ideas You can make a website without knowing much or any html/css; there are tools that let you do a lot in plain text and R instead.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
