<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Computational Demography @UW</title>
    <link>/computational-demography/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Computational Demography @UW</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/computational-demography/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Last CDWG of the Quarter and Ian Kennedy Workshop on R and sqlite and psql</title>
      <link>/computational-demography/post/2021-03-08-tbd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computational-demography/post/2021-03-08-tbd/</guid>
      <description>Abstract</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ben Gibson, RAND and Research Plan Development Follow Up</title>
      <link>/computational-demography/post/2021-03-01-tbd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computational-demography/post/2021-03-01-tbd/</guid>
      <description>Special Time: 2-4PM
Bio: Ben Gibson is an Associate Behavioral Scientist at RAND. His work involves applied and methodological research on social networks with a focus on policy, especially health policy. He&amp;rsquo;s currently working on network models that explore the origin of the race gap in healthcare utilization, peer network models for gender- and race-related disparities in education, relational event dynamics of networked communication, and methodological problems in computing large-scale ERGMs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet a Research Sociologist - Sean Fitzhugh, ARL</title>
      <link>/computational-demography/post/2021-02-22-tbd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computational-demography/post/2021-02-22-tbd/</guid>
      <description>Bio Dr. Sean Fitzhugh is a Research Sociologist in the U.S. Army Research Laboratory’s Human Research and Engineering Directorate. He specializes in developing and applying innovative methodologies for collecting, analyzing, and modeling network data. While his methodological work spans many domains across the social sciences, his substantive work focuses on emergent behavior in task-oriented groups. Prior to joining ARL in 2016, Dr. Fitzhugh was a postdoctoral fellow with the National Academy of Sciences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet a Sociologist - Ben Gibson, Rand Corp [New time 200PM March 01]</title>
      <link>/computational-demography/post/2021-02-15-tbd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computational-demography/post/2021-02-15-tbd/</guid>
      <description>Special Time: 2-3PM
Bio: Ben Gibson is an Associate Behavioral Scientist at RAND. His work involves applied and methodological research on social networks with a focus on policy, especially health policy. He&amp;rsquo;s currently working on network models that explore the origin of the race gap in healthcare utilization, peer network models for gender- and race-related disparities in education, relational event dynamics of networked communication, and methodological problems in computing large-scale ERGMs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet a Data Scientist - Christopher Marcum, NIH</title>
      <link>/computational-demography/post/data-science-talk-christopher-marcum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computational-demography/post/data-science-talk-christopher-marcum/</guid>
      <description>Talk title: Sociology in Practice: Methods and Madness of a Sociologist at the National Institutes of Health
Bio Dr. Christopher Steven Marcum is a staff scientist of data science strategy in the Office of Data Science and Emerging Technologies at the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID). A mathematical sociologist by training, he received his PhD from UC-Irvine in 2011 and subsequently completed a postdoctoral fellowship in economics and statistics at RAND.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet a Social Scientist - Ande Reisman, Adobe</title>
      <link>/computational-demography/post/2021-02-01-tbd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computational-demography/post/2021-02-01-tbd/</guid>
      <description>Bio Ande Reisman got her PhD in Sociology from the University of Washington in 2018 after doing a qualitative dissertation based in Nepal. Since graduation she&amp;rsquo;s made the transition into technology as a UX Researcher, currently at Adobe in Salt Lake City, Utah and at a start-up prior to that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet a Data Scientist - Haema Nilakanta</title>
      <link>/computational-demography/post/data-science-talk-haema-nilakanta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computational-demography/post/data-science-talk-haema-nilakanta/</guid>
      <description>Bio Haema Nilakanta received her PhD from the University of Minnesota, School of Statistics. Her research interests include Monte Carlo theory and methods, computational statistics, network analysis, and statistical applications to public health and population studies. Haema is based in Minneapolis and is currently an AI Scientist for Target.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canceled for MLK</title>
      <link>/computational-demography/post/2021-01-18-tbd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computational-demography/post/2021-01-18-tbd/</guid>
      <description>Canceled for MLK Holiday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connor Gilroy - Workshop on word embeddings for the social sciences</title>
      <link>/computational-demography/post/2021-01-11-nih-marcum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computational-demography/post/2021-01-11-nih-marcum/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Word embeddings are a relatively new tool for computational text analysis. This workshop will explain what word embeddings are and give examples of how they have been used in cultural sociology and political science. I&amp;rsquo;ll then demonstrate some of these uses of word embeddings, including methods for word similarity, semantic change over time, document conceptual engagement, and binary concept construction. This hands-on tutorial will draw on in-progress dissertation work examining discourse about &amp;ldquo;community&amp;rdquo; in English.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to CDWG</title>
      <link>/computational-demography/post/welcome-to-the-first-meeting-of-the-new-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computational-demography/post/welcome-to-the-first-meeting-of-the-new-year/</guid>
      <description>The first meeting of CDWG will be used to introduce its members and kick of Winter quarter CDWG. A general discussion of the goals of the group as well as upcoming topics in brown bag, professional development, research talks and workshops will be discussed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
