<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Computational Demography @UW</title>
    <link>/computational-demography/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Computational Demography @UW</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/computational-demography/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a Research Website</title>
      <link>/computational-demography/post/making-a-research-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computational-demography/post/making-a-research-website/</guid>
      <description>Why make a website? Academic researchers need to communicate their work!
Several kinds of websites can be useful for this:
 a personal academic homepage a page for a specific research project a website for a course a website for a working group or seminar (like CDWG!)  Key ideas You can make a website without knowing much or any html/css; there are tools that let you do a lot in plain text and R instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Populating the Globe with World Pop</title>
      <link>/computational-demography/post/populating-the-globe-with-worldpop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computational-demography/post/populating-the-globe-with-worldpop/</guid>
      <description>This week&amp;rsquo;s meeting of the CSDE-CWG was led by Nathan Welch from the Department of Statistics here at the University of Washington. Nathan walked us through his experience attending the Inaugural World Pop Winter School, a brief course that looks to introduce students, government workers, and NGO employees on the geographic resources produced by World Pop.
The Agenda of World Pop As stated on the Word Pop website the goals of the organization are to &amp;ldquo;Meet the needs of [contemporary data on human population distributions] through the provision of detailed and open-access population distribution dataset built using transparent approaches.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>