<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computational Demography @UW</title>
    <link>/computational-demography/author/zack-almquist/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Computational Demography @UW</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/computational-demography/author/zack-almquist/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Memorial Day Holiday - NO Meeting</title>
      <link>/computational-demography/post/2021-05-31-tbd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computational-demography/post/2021-05-31-tbd/</guid>
      <description>Memorial Day Holiday. No meeting</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paul Smaldino, UC Merced - An Introduction to (Agent-Based) Modeling</title>
      <link>/computational-demography/post/2021-05-24-tbd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computational-demography/post/2021-05-24-tbd/</guid>
      <description>An Introduction to (Agent-Based) Modeling
What are formal models, and what these &amp;ldquo;agents&amp;rdquo; on which some of them are apparently based? How might they help us to be better scientists? These are the questions I will attempt to answer. In addition, I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about some insights from modeling contagions, and how scientists interested in modeling can get started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tim Thomas, Research Director, Urban Displacement Project, University of California, Berkeley</title>
      <link>/computational-demography/post/2021-05-17-tbd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computational-demography/post/2021-05-17-tbd/</guid>
      <description>Bio</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brian C. O&#39;Neill, Director of the Joint Global Change Research Institute</title>
      <link>/computational-demography/post/2021-05-10-tbd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computational-demography/post/2021-05-10-tbd/</guid>
      <description>Brian O&amp;rsquo;Neill is an Earth systems scientist who studies the relationship between future societal development, emissions and climate change impacts—has been named the new director of the Joint Global Change Research Institute.
The institute is a partnership between the U.S. Department of Energy&amp;rsquo;s Pacific Northwest National Laboratory and the University of Maryland in College Park, MD. It brings together expertise in research, modeling and analysis to advance scientific understanding of the ways in which human, energy and environmental systems interact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Micheal Pollard, Rand Corp</title>
      <link>/computational-demography/post/2021-05-03-tbd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computational-demography/post/2021-05-03-tbd/</guid>
      <description>Michael S. Pollard is a senior sociologist at the RAND Corporation and a professor at the Pardee RAND Graduate School. His primary research areas include demography, family, and social networks and health (physical, mental, and health behaviors). His recent work has focused on the health implications of different types of friendship and romantic relationships, including an on-going five-year project tracking adult social networks and alcohol use using nationally representative data. He also studies voter beliefs and behaviors, and lead the RAND 2016 Presidential Election Panel Survey project, tracking voter beliefs and intentions for a year leading up to the election, as well as leading 2014 and 2018 midterm election studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PAA Practice Talks</title>
      <link>/computational-demography/post/2021-04-26-tbd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computational-demography/post/2021-04-26-tbd/</guid>
      <description>We are saving this session for PAA practice talks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Talk - Digital Divisions, Matt Rafalow, Research Scientist Google</title>
      <link>/computational-demography/post/2021-04-19-tbd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computational-demography/post/2021-04-19-tbd/</guid>
      <description>Education researchers struggle with the fact that students arrive at school already shaped by their unequal childhoods. Would we see greater gains among less privileged students if they had a more level playing field? This talk draws on a comparative ethnographic study of three middle schools to address this question, focusing the case of digital technology use. In the contemporary moment, kids’ digital skills appear in the form of their digital play with peers, like through social media use, video gaming, and creating online content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TBD</title>
      <link>/computational-demography/post/2021-04-12-tbd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computational-demography/post/2021-04-12-tbd/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matt Rafalow, Research Scientist Google</title>
      <link>/computational-demography/post/2021-04-05-tbd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computational-demography/post/2021-04-05-tbd/</guid>
      <description>Matt Rafalow is a Visiting Scholar at UC Berkeley&amp;rsquo;s Center for Science, Technology, Medicine and Society, and a social scientist at Google. His book, Digital Divisions: How Schools Create Inequality in the Tech Era, just published with University of Chicago Press. He is also co-author of Affinity Online: How Connection and Shared Interests Fuel Learning (NYU Press, 2018). His work has appeared in journals such as American Journal of Sociology, Symbolic Interaction, and Social Currents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to CDWG</title>
      <link>/computational-demography/post/welcome-to-the-first-meeting-of-the-quarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computational-demography/post/welcome-to-the-first-meeting-of-the-quarter/</guid>
      <description>The first meeting of CDWG will be used to introduce its members and kick of Spring quarter CDWG. A general discussion of the goals of the group as well as upcoming topics in brown bag, professional development, research talks and workshops will be discussed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
