<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computational Demography @UW</title>
    <link>/computational-demography/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Computational Demography @UW</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/computational-demography/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Differential Privacy and the US Census</title>
      <link>/computational-demography/post/differential-privacy-census/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computational-demography/post/differential-privacy-census/</guid>
      <description>Lee Fiorio (Geography) presented joint work with Neal Marquez (Sociology) on the implications of differential privacy in the 2020 US Census for policy and social science research:
 In an attempt to better safeguard the information that Census Bureau collects from the public, the Bureau has committed to deploy a variation of differential privacy on the 2020 Census and all census products moving forward. This noise injection process has the potential to better protect the private information of individuals, however, the cost to accuracy of statistical measures is not well understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discussion and Looking Forward</title>
      <link>/computational-demography/post/discussion-and-looking-forward/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computational-demography/post/discussion-and-looking-forward/</guid>
      <description>At the final meeting of the 2018-2019 academic year, we brainstormed ideas for the coming year. We discussed potential speakers, including incoming UW faculty, substantive topics of relevance to the group, and technical topics for tutorials. One idea that emerged was having a series of tutorials throughout the year on creating an R package of benefit to academic researchers. Many participants felt that a package implementing common tools for working with neighborhood-level spatial data would be useful to us, since we often build those tools on our own in an ad-hoc way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Analysis for Demography</title>
      <link>/computational-demography/post/text4demog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computational-demography/post/text4demog/</guid>
      <description>On March 7, 2019, Ian Kennedy, a graduate student from Sociology, led a tutorial and discussion about analyzing text data for demographic research.
Based on his research projects using data from Craigslist and Twitter, he presented on applications of keyword matching, n-gram regression, topic modeling, and word embeddings.
The RMarkdown and Jupyter notebooks for his tutorial can be found on GitHub at the following repository:
https://github.com/ikennedy240/text4demog</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a Research Website</title>
      <link>/computational-demography/post/making-a-research-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computational-demography/post/making-a-research-website/</guid>
      <description>Why make a website? Academic researchers need to communicate their work!
Several kinds of websites can be useful for this:
 a personal academic homepage a page for a specific research project a website for a course a website for a working group or seminar (like CDWG!)  Key ideas You can make a website without knowing much or any html/css; there are tools that let you do a lot in plain text and R instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WorldPop</title>
      <link>/computational-demography/post/worldpop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computational-demography/post/worldpop/</guid>
      <description>On January 31, 2019, Nathan Welch, a graduate student in Statistics, led a stimulating discussion about the value and uses of the WorldPop project. WorldPop is an open-data resource for spatial demographics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roundtable on Facebook Ads</title>
      <link>/computational-demography/post/roundtable-fb-ads/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computational-demography/post/roundtable-fb-ads/</guid>
      <description>On December 6, 2018, CDWG held a roundtable on using Facebook advertising platform data for demographic research. Three UW graduate students with active projects using Facebook ads data led the conversation:
Lee Fiorio (geography) investigates the possibility of combining traditional data on migrants with estimates of migrants from Facebook Ads to produce more detailed cross-tabulations than available from traditional data sources. Using data from Facebook Ads as the seed, he uses Iterative Proportional Fitting to estimate a three-dimensional cross tabulation (migrant stocks by age by sex) from UN-published migrant data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git and GitHub Workflows for Research</title>
      <link>/computational-demography/post/git-github-workflows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computational-demography/post/git-github-workflows/</guid>
      <description>For our first meeting of the 2018-2019 academic year, on November 15, Tim Thomas led a workshop on git and GitHub workflows for demographic research. Tim is a data science postdoc at the eScience Institute and in Sociology.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>